Arbaaz Sumar

Front End Developer

Frontend developer with over two years of hands-on experience in identifying web-based user interactions along with designing & implementing highly-responsive user interface components by deploying React concepts. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology, and writing application interface code via JavaScript and ReactJS workflows.

arbaaz970@gmail.com

+254705913300

Nairobi, Kenya Relocation / Remote Possible

GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

Experience

11/2020 to present

Front End Developer

Freelance, Remote

- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Created a user experience that fetched, parsed, and formatted analytic data, and relayed it into React components.
- Built mock designs and wireframes for landing pages for 5 new product concepts.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5, and CSS3, which improved user satisfaction by 40%.
- Designed and developed web applications using React.js to increase target audience engagement by 15%.

05/2020 to 10/2020

Junior Front End Developer Real Biz Digital LTD, Nairobi

- Created a Mobile Responsive User Experience with CSS
 Flexbox that allowed cross-platform accessibility to the
 website on any device with primary use on mobile. This
 increased the number of 5-star User Experience/User
 Interface reviews by 360%
- Assisted the development team in maintaining 8 websites.
- Implemented front-end technical solutions to meet project requirements for creation of 5 new web pages.
- Enhanced user experience and accomplish webpage objectives by creating site structure, navigation, page optimization, and graphics integration.
- Conducted research and assisted with new business scoping efforts, resulting in the acquisition of 4 clients.
- Worked in an Agile, collaborative environment to receive design requirements, peer program, and test applications.

Skills

HTML, CSS,
JavaScript/TypeScript
ReactJs, Redux, jQuery
Python, PHP, SQL
React Native
Git, Mocha

Education

Bachelor of Science: Applied Computer & Technology

2016–2020 Nairobi, Kenya

United States International University Africa

Certifications

Frontend Developer Career Path

Scrimba

Responsive Web Design

freeCodeCamp